Robert S. Phillips Papers
Robert S. Phillips Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Lunday, Robert
    - "Two Cannibals", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Lust, Herbert
    - "Letter to Frederick", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Luttinger, Abigail (Box 6A)
  - Lyman, Henry (Box 6A)
  - Lyons, Steve
    - "The Bandit", ms. (Box 6A)
    - "Erin and the Black Widow", ms. (Box 6A)
    - "The Gift of Tongues", ms. (Box 6A)
    - "Modernday Wrecks", ms. (Box 6A)
    - "On Top of the World", ms. (Box 6A)
    - "The Perfect Falls", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Macdonald, Cynthia (Box 6A)
  - Macdonald, Dwight (Box 6A)
  - Macdonald, Nancy (Box 6A)
  - Mack, Maynard (Box 6A)
  - Madden, David (Box 6A)
  - Mailer, Norman (Box 6A)
  - Makuck, Peter (Box 6A)
  - Malamud, Bernard (Box 6A)
  - Malanga, Gerard (Box 6A)
  - Malin, Irving (Box 6A)
  - Malzberg, Barry N. (Box 6A)
  - Manhattan Poetry Review (Box 6A)
  - The Manhattan Review, See Fried, Philip
  - Manley, Seon (Box 6A)
  - Marcus, Lawrence B.
    - "The Stunt Man", ms. (Box 6A)
  - Marks, Corey (Box 6A)
  - Martin, Alastair B.
    - "In Happy Holmes He Saw the Light, or the Fishing Poll", ms. (Box 7)
  - Martin, Charles
    - "The Poems of Catullus", photocopy of published translation (Box 7)
  - Martz, William J. (Box 7)
  - Mason, Bobbie Ann (Box 7)
  - Mason, David
    - "The Country I Remember: a Narrative", ms. (Box 7)
    - "The Day When Night Stays On", ms. (Box 7)
  - Mathis, Cleopatra
    - "Guardian" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 7)
  - Maxwell, William (Box 7)
  - Mazzaro, Jerome
    - "The Caves of Love", ms. (Box 7)
    - "Figurations of Jerome", ms. (Box 7)
    - Interview of Robert Phillips (Box 7)
  - McCarthy, Mary (Box 7)
  - McCullers, Carson (Box 7)
  - McDonald, Walter (Box 7)
  - McDowell, Robert (Box 7)
  - McFee, Michael (Box 7)
  - McGraw, DeLoss (Box 7)
  - McGuire, Jerry
    - McKenna, Rosalie Thorne "Rollie" (Box 7)
  - McKinley, Georgia (Box 7)
  - McMahon, Lynne (Box 7)
  - McNamara, Peter L. (Box 7)
  - McPherson, Bruce (Box 7)
  - McPherson, James Alan
    - "Elbow Room", page proofs (Box 7)
  - McPherson, Sandra (Box 7)
  - McPhillips, Robert T.
    - "The Mother and the Emergence of the Female Voice in Oates' Fiction", ms. (Box 7)
    - "Robert Phillips" - Dictionary of Literary Biography, ms. (Box 7)
  - Mendelson, Edward (Box 8)
  - Meredith, William (Box 8)
  - Merrill, James Ingram (Box 8)
  - Merwin, William Stanley (Box 8)
  - Miles, Barbara (Box 8)
  - Miles, Sylvia (Box 8)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 8)
  - Miller, Jennifer
    - "Just an Old-Fashioned Girl", ms. (Box 8)
  - Miller, Jim Wayne (Box 8)
  - Miller, Merle (Box 8)
  - Miller, Wayne
    - "Only the Senses Sleep", ms. (Box 8)
  - Mills, Ralph J. (Box 8)
  - Miner, Katy
    - "Dog Park", ms. (Box 8)
  - Mizener, Rosemary (Mrs. Arthur) (Box 8)
  - Monitor Book Company, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Moore, Marianne (Box 8)
  - Morgan, Frederick
    - "Northbook", page proofs; See also The Hudson Review (Box 8)
  - Morley, Hilda (Box 8)
  - Morris, Robert K. (Box 8)
  - Morris, Wright
    - "Words and Photographs", ms. (Box 8)
  - Morrison, Theodore (Box 8)
  - Mosel, Tad (Box 8)
  - Moss, Howard, See The New Yorker
  - Mueller, Lisel (Box 8)
  - Muirhead, Eric
    - "Songs of Prince Vogelfrei", ms. (Box 8)
    - Stories, ms.; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Mullen, Laura
    - "The Surface", ms. (Box 8)
  - Murr, Naeem (Box 8)
  - Murray, G. E.
    - "Oils of Evening" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 8)
  - Nagle, Christian
    - Poems, ms. (Box 8)
  - Nathaniel, Isabel
    - "The Dominion of Lights", ms. (Box 8)
  - The Nation (Box 8)
  - National Book Awards, 1995 (Box 8)
  - National Book Foundation (Box 8)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 8)
  - Negative Capability (Box 8A)
  - Nelson, Marie Coleman (Box 8A)
  - The New Criterion (Box 8A)
  - New Directions (Box 8A)
  - New England Review (Box 8A)
  - New York Public Library (Box 8A)
  - The New Yorker (Box 8A)
  - Nichols, Jeannette (Box 8A)
  - Nims, John Frederick (Box 8A)
  - Nobles, Edward (Box 8A)
  - Norman, Dorothy (Box 8A)
  - [W. W.] Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 8A)
  - Nye, Naomi Shihab (Box 8A)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol
    All Oates material is restricted.
    - Correspondence, 1959-2003; 22 folders (Box 0)
    - "The Doll", ms. (Box 0)
    - "Gulf War", ms. (Box 0)
    - "I Lock the Door Upon Myself", galleys (Box 0)
    - "The Interview", ms. (Box 0)
    - "Pseudonymous Selves", ms. (Box 0)
    - "The Rehearsal", ms. (Box 0)
    - "The Sacrifice", ms. (Box 0)
      See also Writings: Interviews
  - Ochester, Ed (Box 8A)
  - O'Connor, Mark
    - "This Way to the Egress", ms. (Box 8A)
  - O'Connor, Mary (Box 8A)
  - O'Connor, William Van (Box 8A)
  - O'Dwyer, Caley (Box 8A)
  - Offit, Sidney (Box 8A)
  - Ohannessian, Griselda, See New Directions
  - Olds, Sharon (Box 8A)
  - The Ontario Review, See Smith, Raymond J.
  - Orchises Press (Box 8A)
  - Orsini, Georgianna (Box 8A)
  - Osborne, James Barney
    - "Holy Smokes", ms. (Box 8A)
    - "What Lips My Lips Have Kissed", ms. (Box 8A)
  - Ostriker, Alicia (Box 8A)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 8A)
  - Ozick, Cynthia (Box 8A)
  - Pacernick, Gary (Box 8A)
  - Padgett, Ron
    - "New & Selected Poems" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 8A)
  - Palmer, Phoebe
    - George Anthony [Palmer]/Charles Crowell correspondence (Box 8A)
  - Papp, Joseph (Box 8A)
  - The Paris Review (Box 8A)
  - Parisi, Joseph, See Poetry
  - Parker, Alan Michael (Box 8A)
  - Parsons, Dave (Box 8A)
  - Partisan Review (Box 8A)
  - Patten, Robert L. (Box 8A)
  - Patterson, Leslie Jill, See Dark Horse Literary Review
  - Peacock, Molly
    - "Raw Heaven", ms. (Box 8A)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes (Box 8A)
  - Peich, Michael (Box 8A)
  - Pen American Center (Box 8A)
  - Pennoyer, Robert M., See also [Mrs. Giles] Whiting Foundation (Box 8A)
  - Pennoyer, Victoria
    - "Field Magic", ms. (Box 8A)
    - "Poems", ms. (Box 8A)
    - "Third Floor", ms. (Box 8A)
    - "A View Through the Window", ms. (Box 8A)
  - Perilo, Lucia Maria
    - "The Body Mutinies", ms. (Box 8A)
  - Perkins, David (Box 8A)
  - Perry, Paul (Box 8A)
  - Peter, Harry W. (Box 8A)
  - Philbrick, Stephen
    - "Half Ain't Been Told", ms. (Box 9)
    - "Half Ain't Been Told and Fourteen Short Poems", ms. (Box 9)
    - "My Bones Believe", ms. (Box 9)
    - "Poems", ms. (Box 9)
    - "Up to the Elbow" (6 versions), ms. (Box 9)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 9)
  - Phillips, Carl
    - "Cortege" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 9)
  - Phillips, Louis (Box 9)
  - Phillips, T. A. and Mrs. (parents), 1968-1972 (Box 9)
  - Phillips, William, See Partisan Review
  - Piskor, Frank (Box 9)
  - Plimpton, George, See The Paris Review
  - Plouffe, Fran Vincent (Box 9)
  - Plouffe, Paul
    - "T Sector", ms. (Box 9)
  - Plumly, Stanley (Box 9)
  - Poetry (Box 9)
  - Poetry Society of America (Box 9)
  - Poets & Writers (Box 9)
  - Poets House (Box 9)
  - Polito, Robert
    - "Doubles" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 9)
  - Pollet, Elizabeth
    - "April Fool's Day", ms. (Box 9)
    - "A Cold-Water Flat", ms. (Box 9)
    - "Darius Alexander Amenhotep", ms. (Box 9)
  - Introduction to Portrait of Delmore, ms. (Box 9)
  - [Murray] Pollinger (literary agency) (Box 9)
  - Poulin, A.
    - "Letters from the Tower", ms. (Box 9)
    - "A Momentary Order", page proofs (Box 9)
    - Writings (ms.) (Box 9)
  - Prairie Schooner (Box 10)
  - Prenshaw, Peggy Whitman (Box 10)
  - Price, Reynolds (Box 10)
  - Princeton University Library (Box 10)
  - Prospere, Susan (Box 10)
  - Raab, Lawrence (Box 10)
  - Rackin, Donald (Box 10)
  - Rainer, Dachine (Box 10)
  - Rainsford, Christina (Box 10)
  - Raisor, Philip (Box 10)
  - Raiziss, Sonia, See Chelsea
  - Ramke, Bin (Box 10)
  - Random House, Inc. (Box 10)
  - Read, Herbert Edward (Box 10)
  - Reeves, Rosser
    - "Popo", page proofs (Box 10)
  - Regan, Jennifer
    - "Futures", ms. (Box 10)
  - Reid, Jan (Box 10)
  - Reiter, Thomas (Box 10)
  - Repusseau, Patrice (Box 10)
  - Rice, Stan
    - "Fear Itself" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 10)
  - Rich, Adrienne (Box 10)
  - Rifenburgh, Daniel
    - "Skip Tracer", ms. (Box 10)
  - Roberts, Doris (Box 10)
  - Robinson, Roxana (Box 10)
  - Robison, James (Box 10)
  - Robison, Mary (Box 10)
  - Root, William Pitt (Box 10)
  - Rorem, Ned (Box 10)
  - Rosen, Michael A. (Box 10)
  - Rosenthal, Macha Louis (Box 10)
  - Ross, Jamie (Box 10)
  - Roy, Cody
    - "Striped Regret", ms. (Box 10)
  - Rubenstein, Carol (Box 10)
  - Rubin, Louis Decimus (Box 10)
  - Rubin, Mark
    - "Errors on the Side of Justice" (excerpts), ms. (Box 10)
    - "Should the Moons Come Over", ms. (Box 10)
  - Rudat, Wolfgang E. H. (Box 10)
  - Rudman, Mark
    - "The Nowhere Steps", ms. (Box 10)
  - Rudnik, Raphael (Box 10)
  - Ruffin, Paul (Box 10)
  - Russell, Howard Lewis
    - "Iced Tea and Ignorance", ms. (Box 10)
    - "Indifference", ms. (Box 10)
    - "Rickety Red Wagon", ms. (Box 10)
    - "The Wedding Cake Couple", ms. (Box 10)
    - Untitled, ms. (3 versions) (Box 10)
  - Salzman, Jack (Box 10)
  - Samaras, Nicholas (Box 10)
  - Sanders, Tony (Box 10)
  - Sandoe, James (Box 10)
  - Sauter, Edwin (Box 10)
  - Scagliotta, Denise (Box 10)
  - Schapiro, Meyer (Box 10)
  - Schechter, Ruth Lisa (Box 10)
  - Schneberger, Kevin
    - "The Breaking of Surilan", ms. (Box 10)
    - "Gilran and Myra", ms. (Box 10)
    - "Kajalim's Constructs", ms. (Box 10)
  - Schneider, Nina (Box 10)
  - Schucker, Charles (Box 10)
  - Schulman, Grace
    - "Hemispheres", ms. (Box 10)
  - Schulz, Gavin (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Delmore
    - "The Heights of Joy", ms. (copy) (Box 10)
    - "In Dreams Begin Responsibilities", a film treatment by Peter Kline and Michele Civetta (Box 10)
    - Essays, incomplete ms. (copies) (Box 10)
    - Poems, ms. copies (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Kenneth (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Lillian (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Lynne Sharon (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Rebecca Spears (Box 10)
  - Scott, Martin
    - "Blues at Sunrise", ms. (Box 10)
    - "Deals with the Devil", ms. (2 versions) (Box 10)
    - Poems, ms. (Box 10)
  - The Scribner Encyclopedia of American Lives (Box 10)
  - Seidman, Hugh
    - "People Live, They Have Lives", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Selden, Lawrence E.
    - "New Losses Arrive Daily", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Serpas, Martha
    - "Cote Blanche", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Sewell, Elizabeth (Box 10A)
  - Seyburn, Patty (Box 10A)
  - Shah, Jacquelyn
    - "Finding Paradise", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Shapiro, Karl Jay and Sophie Wilkins
    - "Notes on Raising a Poet", ms. (Box 10A)
    - "The Old Horsefly" (formerly: "No Funeral"), ms. (Box 10A)
    - "The Wild Card", 2 versions of ms. in 2 folders (Box 10A)
    - "The Wild Card", production records (Box 10A)
    - The Wild Card (Urbana: University of Illinois Press), c1998; See also Writings: Interviews; Writings: Miscellaneous: Tapes (Box 29) (Box 10A)
  - Shaw, Robert Burns (Box 10A)
  - Shenandoah (Box 10A)
  - Shepherd, Reginald
    - "Some Are Drowning", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Sher, Ira (Box 10A)
  - Sherwin, Judith Johnson (Box 10A)
  - Shinder, Jason (Box 10A)
  - Shipley, Vivian
    - "A Cormorant in the Tree", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Short, Roberta Harris
    - "Mariana", ms. (Box 10A)
  - Shrifte, Evelyn, See Vanguard Press, Inc.
  - Sidhwa, Bapsi (Box 10B)
  - Siegel, George (Box 10B)
  - Silbert, Layle (Box 10B)
  - Silex, Edgar Gabriel
    - "Through All the Displacements" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 10B)
  - Silverton, Michael
    - "The Enchanted Kielbasa", ms. (Box 10B)
  - Simon, John (Box 10B)
  - Simpson, Eileen B. (Box 10B)
  - Simpson, Louis (Box 10B)
  - Sissman, L. E. (Box 10B)
  - Slaughter, Adele
    - "The Book of Denial", ms. (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Charlie
    - "Segunda Segundo", ms. (Box 10B)
    - Untitled poetry collection, ms. (Box 10B)
  - Smith, David Jeddie, See also The Southern Review (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Franc (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Lee (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Oliver (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Raymond J. (Box 10B)
  - Smith, William Jay
    - "The Cherokee Lottery", ms. (Box 10B)
    - "Collected Poems ", 1938-1998; ms. (Box 10B)
    - "The World Below the Window", ms.; See also Writings: Miscellaneous: Tapes (Box 29) (Box 10B)
  - Smith, Winn and Lawrence Beall (Box 10B)
  - [Gibbs] Smith, Publisher (Box 10B)
  - Snodgrass, William De Witt
    - Writings (Box 10B)
  - Snow, Edward A. (Box 10B)
  - Snyder, Thomas
    - "True Poems", ms. (Box 11)
    - Ms. essays (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Ms. poems (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Miscellany (Box 11)
  - Sofranko, Michael (Box 11)
  - Sontag, Susan (Box 11)
  - Southern Illinois University Press (Box 11)
  - The Southern Review (Box 11)
  - Southwell, Samuel B. and Mary (Box 11)
  - Southwest Review (Box 11)
  - Spanfeller, James J. (Box 11)
  - Spence, June (Box 11)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth
    All Spencer material is restricted.
    - Correspondence, 1971-2003; undated; 18 folders (Box 41)
    - "The Boy in the Tree", ms. (Box 41)
    - "The Cousins", ms. (Box 41)
    - "For Lease or Sale", ms. (Box 41)
    - "How It All Was" (alternate title: "Touching Bases"), ms. (Box 41)
    - "Indian Summer", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Jack of Diamonds", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Jean-Pierre", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Lake George", ms. (Box 41)
    - "The Lost Children", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Madame Delida", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Madonna", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Mr. Busby", ms. (Box 41)
    - "The Night Travellers", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Ocean Isle", ms. (Box 41)
    - "On Pinehurst Street", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Owl", ms. (Box 41)
    - "The Puzzle Poem", ms. (Box 41)
    - "Shadow Play", ms. (Box 42)
    - "Shongalo", ms. (Box 42)
    - "The Stud", ms. (Box 42)
    - "Touching Bases" (alternate title: "How It All Was"), ms. (Box 42)
    - "Tryptich", ms. (Box 42)
    - "Two By Moonlight", ms. (Box 42)
    - "Up the Gatineau", ms. (Box 42)
    - "The Weekend Travellers", ms. (Box 42)
    - James Randall Woodland, "In that city foreign and paradoxical: The idea of New Orleans in the Southern literary imagination", dissertation, includes discussion of Spencer's work (Box 42)
    - Printed material, miscellaneous (Box 42)
  - Spender, Stephen (Box 11)
  - Stackpole, Scott (Box 11)
  - Stark, Stephen
    - "Positive", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Virgin", ms. (Box 11)
  - Stefanik, Ernest C. (Box 11)
  - Steingut, Stanley (Box 11)
  - Steloff, Frances (Box 11)
  - Stepanchev, Stephen (Box 11)
  - Stern, Daniel
    - "The Altman Sonata", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Apraxia", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Chaos", ms.. (Box 11)
    - "Comfort", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Exchange", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Fellowship", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Found and Lost", ms. (2 versions) (Box 11)
    - "Foxx Hunting", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Grievances and Griefs", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Hallucinosis", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Imperato Placeless", ms. (Box 11)
    - "In the Country of the Young", ms. (Box 11)
    - "A Little Street Music", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Lunch with Gottlieb" (Part 1), ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Man on the Dump By Wallace Stevens: a Story", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Man Who Would Not", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Messenger", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The One Thing She Would Not Do", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Oven Bird By Robert Frost", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Road Not Taken By Robert Frost: a Story", ms. (Box 11)
    - "The Second Coming By W. B. Yeats", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Time Will Tell", ms. (Box 11)
    - "Visions and Revisions", ms. (Box 11)
  - Stern, Joan
    - "Fractured Light", ms. (Box 11)
  - Sternburg, Janet (Box 11)
  - Stever, Margo
    - "Reading the Night Sky", ms. (Box 11A)
  - Stewart, Susan
    - "The Forest" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 11A)
  - Stoehr, Taylor (Box 11A)
  - Stokes, Terry (Box 11A)
  - Stokesbury, Leon (Box 11A)
  - Stolzenberg, Jonathan
    - "The Won Back Heart", ms. (Box 11A)
  - Stone, Lewis H. (Box 11A)
  - Storey, Gail Donohue (Box 11A)
  - Story Line Press, See McDowell, Robert
  - Strand, Mark (Box 11A)
  - Strandberg, Victor (Box 11A)
  - Stuart, Dabney, See also Shenandoah (Box 11A)
  - Styron, William (Box 11A)
  - Suarez, Virgil (Box 11A)
  - Sullivan, Margaret (Box 11A)
  - Sutton, Walter (Box 11A)
  - Swenson, Karen (Box 11A)
  - Swenson, May (Box 11A)
  - Symons, Julian (Box 11A)
  - Syracuse University (Box 11A)
  - Syracuse University Press (Box 11A)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 11A)
  - Tatham, David (Box 11A)
  - Taylor, A. L. (Box 11A)
  - Taylor, Henry (Box 11A)
  - Taylor, Peter (Box 11A)
  - Taylor, Ross, See Taylor, A. L.
  - Ten Eyck, Drew (Box 11A)
  - Terris, Virginia (Box 11A)
  - Terry-Thomas (Box 11A)
  - Texas Book Festival (Box 11A)
  - Texas Institute of Letters (Box 11A)
  - Thomas, James (Box 11A)
  - Thomas, Larry D. (Box 11A)
  - Thompson, Phyllis (Box 11A)
  - Thwaite, Anthony (Box 11A)
  - Tillinghast, Richard (Box 11A)
  - Tolley, William Pearson (Box 11A)
  - Trachtman, Paula (Box 11A)
  - Trevor, William (Box 11A)
  - Trilling, Diana (Box 11A)
  - Triquarterly, See Gibbons, Reginald
  - Truesdale, Calvin William (Box 11A)
  - Tucker, Martin (Box 11A)
  - Turco, Lewis (Box 11A)
  - Twayne Publishers, Inc. (Box 11A)
  - University of Houston (Box 11B)
  - University of Illinois Press (Box 11B)
  - University of Michigan Press (Box 11B)
  - University of Texas (Box 11B)
  - University of Texas Press (Box 11B)
  - Unterberg Poetry Center (New York, N.Y.) (Box 11B)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 11B)
  - Updike, John (Box 11B)
  - Urdang, Constance (Box 11B)
  - Valentine, Jean (Box 11B)
  - Vanguard Press, Inc. (Box 11B)
  - Vellani, Robert
    - "The Driving Test", ms. (Box 11B)
    - "The Family Show\Red", ms. (Box 11B)
  - Vendler, Helen Hennessy
    - "Poems, Poets, and Poetry", ms. (Box 11B)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box 11B)
  - Viereck, Peter
    - re: "Applewood" (Box 11B)
  - Villatoro, Marcos McPeek
    - They Say That I Am Two, page proofs (Box 11B)
  - Wagner, Charles A. (Box 12)
  - Wagner, Linda W., See Wagner-Martin, Linda
  - Wagner-Martin, Linda (Box 12)
  - Walker, Isaac (Box 12)
  - Walker, Jeanne Murray (Box 12)
  - Walker, Sue, See Negative Capability
  - Wallace, Robert (Box 12)
  - Ward, Aileen (Box 12)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 12)
  - Waters, Michael (Box 12)
  - Watson, George (Box 12)
  - Webb, Paula J. (Box 12)
  - Weidman, Bette S. (Box 12)
  - Weiss, Theodore Russell (Box 12)
  - Wellesley College Library (Box 12)
  - Wells, Lester G. (Box 12)
  - Wesleyan Writers Conference (Box 12)
  - Wetzsteon, Rachel (Box 12)
  - White, James (Box 12)
  - Whitebird, Joanie, See Wings Press (Houston, Texas)
  - Whitehead, William, See E. P. Dutton, Inc.
  - Whiteside, George (Box 12)
  - [Mrs. Giles] Whiting Foundation (Box 12)
  - Whittemore, Reed (Box 12)
  - Wier, Allen (Box 12)
  - Wieser & Wieser, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Wilbur, Richard (Box 12)
  - Wilentz, Theodore (Box 12)
  - Wilkins Sophie, See Shapiro, Karl Jay and Sophie Wilkins
  - Willard, Charles H. (Box 12)
  - Willhardt, Mark (Box 12)
  - Williams, George
    - "Before I Wake", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Under a Green Sun", ms. (Box 12A)
  - Williams, John A.
    - Safari West, page proofs (Box 12A)
  - Williams, Miller (Box 12A)
  - Williamson, Alan
    - "Love and the Soul" (1995 National Book Awards entry), page proofs (Box 12A)
  - Williamson, Eleanor (Box 12A)
  - Williamson, Eric Miles
    - "Another New Father", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Blue Note", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Blue Train", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Cyrano Is Dead", ms.
      - "East Bay Grease", ms. (3 versions) (Box 12A)
    - "First and Last Chance", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Food for Powder" (excerpt), ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Four Fictional Positions", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "The Girl Haters Club", ms. (Box 12A)
    - "Hope, Among Other Vices and Virtues", ms.. (Box 12A)
    - "In Defense of James Fennimore Cooper", ms.. (Box 12A)
    - "Mr. Murphy's Wedding", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Music Maker", ms. (Box 13)
    - "New Blood", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Oakland, Jack London, and Me", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Scow", ms. (Box 13)
    - "The Search for the Pleasing Sound: an Interview with Robert Phillips", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Sleep Is for the Day" (excerpt), ms. (Box 13)
    - "The Teachings of Don B." (Box 13)
    - "Thirteen Fictional Positions", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Trading Nights", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Two-up", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Urban Renewal", ms. (Box 13)
  - Williamson, Melissa Studdard
    - "Home Health Maintenance Organization: Instructions for Care of Patient", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Noah's Ark", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Old Romeo", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Witch Doctor", ms. (Box 13)
  - Wilson, Edmund (Box 13)
  - Wilson, Michael
    - "The Kiddie Pool", ms. (Box 13)
  - Wilson, Sandy (Box 13)
  - Wings Press (Houston, Texas) (Box 13)
  - Winniford, Lee
    - "Quails", ms. (Box 13)
  - Wissot, Lauren
    - "Deviants 'R' Us", ms. (Box 13)
    - "Eternal Happiness and the Nightclub Conspiracy", ms. (Box 13)
  - Woll, Bernice S., See also Vanguard Press, Inc. (Box 13)
  - Woll, Thomas (Box 13)
  - Wright, Annie (Mrs. James) (Box 13)
  - Wright, Jay (Box 13)
  - Wrigley, Robert (Box 13)
  - Wubs, Annemarieke.
    - "Delmore Schwartz: Deconstructing the Legend", ms. (Box 13)
  - Yaddo (Box 13)
  - Yale University Library (Box 13)
  - Yates, Richard (Box 13)
  - Yevtushenko, Yevgeny (autograph)
    - Young, Thomas Daniel/Core, George - "Selected Letters of John Crowe Ransom", page proofs (Box 13)
  - Zagajewski, Adam (Box 13)
  - Zamora, Lois Parkinson
    - "American Books of the Dead", ms. (Box 13)
  - Zaturenska, Marya
    - "The Hidden Waterfall", ms.; See also Writings: Interviews (Box 13)
  - Zinnes, Harriet (Box 13)
  - Zolotow, Maurice (Box 13)
  - Zucker, David
    - "An Unsafe Distance", ms. (Box 13)
    - Autobiography (untitled) (Box 13)
  - Zweig, Paul (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z (Box 14)
- Writings
  - Books
    - Aspects of Alice (Vanguard), 1971
      - Permissions, miscellany (Box 15)
      - Foreword, holograph ms. (Box 15)
      - Foreword, typescript ms. (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, 9 folders (Box 15)
      - Appendix, typescript ms. with corrections (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, miscellany (Box 15)
      - Dust jacket copy (Box 15)
      - Production records
        - Art work (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
        - Galleys, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Aspects of Alice (Vintage Books), 1977
      - Holograph additions, notes (Box 15)
    - Breakdown Lane (Johns Hopkins University Press), 1994
      - Manuscript (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, copyedited (Box 15)
      - Production records
        - Page proofs (Box 15)
        - Page proofs, copyedited (Box 15)
    - The Confessional Poets (Southern Illinois University Press), 1973
      - Introduction, holograph ms. (Box 15)
      - "Notes on the Confessional Mode in Modern American Poetry" - Chapter 1 (Box 15)
      - Manuscript, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Index, manuscript (Box 15)
      - Production records
        - Book cover (Box 15)
        - Galleys (Box 15)
        - Unused material (Box 15)
    - Coward, Noel. The Collected Stories of Noel Coward / uncredited ed., R. Phillips (Dutton, ), 1983
      - Preface, typescript ms. (Box 16)
      - Manuscript, 6 folders (Box 16)
    - Denton Welch (Twayne), 1974
      - Typescript ms., 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Typescript ms., 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Typescript ms., 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous pages, notes (Box 16)
      - Related documentation (Box 16)
      - Production records, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Face to Face (Wings Press), 1993
      - Production records
        - Page proofs (Box 16)
    - Goyen, William. William Goyen: Selected Letters from a Writer's Life (working title: "Selected Letters of William Goyen") (University of Texas Press, ), 1995
      - Introduction, draft, revisions; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Manuscript, 8 folders (Box 16)